<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>compose on maiatoday</title><link>https://maiatoday.github.io/tags/compose/</link><description>Recent content in compose on maiatoday</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 21:38:36 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://maiatoday.github.io/tags/compose/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kibeth Codes twitch highlights 1</title><link>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/kibeth-codes-twitch-highlights-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 21:38:36 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/kibeth-codes-twitch-highlights-1/</guid><description>To practise for live speaking and to explore how to add Jetpack Compose to an existing open source app, I start a twitch stream as kibethcodes. The app I chose to work on is Habitica, a habit tracking/ToDo app that saw it&amp;rsquo;s first commit in 2015.
KibethCodes level 6
Streaming Tuesdays at 19:00 UTC+2
Here are a selection of highlights of the twitch stream.</description></item><item><title>Links to Learn Compose</title><link>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/links-to-learn-compose/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 21:43:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/links-to-learn-compose/</guid><description>At the moment people often ask me where to go start learning Jetpack Compose. Here is a a hand picked selection of my favourite Compose resources. These may change as I find new ones. There should be something for everyone, Official, Community, Videos, Books, Streams.
Official docs Official Docs
Pathway
Official apps Jetpack Compose Samples
Material Catalog
Community websites Jetpackcompose.app
compose.academy
Jetpack Compose Playground
Videos Philip Lackner Compose playist
Coding in Flow</description></item><item><title>Lightning Demo of Compose animation</title><link>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/lightning-demo-of-compose-animation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 21:13:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/lightning-demo-of-compose-animation/</guid><description>A lighting talk for Jozi-JUG demonstrating Compose animation and demo on mobile and desktop.
slides</description></item><item><title>Panel talk on Deep dive into compose</title><link>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/panel-talk-on-deep-dive-into-compose/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 20:34:09 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/panel-talk-on-deep-dive-into-compose/</guid><description>Panel discussion hosted by GDG Cape Town. Interesting discussion at the end of the presentations by Nick and Thomas. Some topics that we discussed was ideas round structuring existing apps and where to put the compose parts, integrating with an existing theme and discussions about Thomas&amp;rsquo;s book.</description></item><item><title>Comparing Declarative Animation frameworks</title><link>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/comparing-declarative-animation-frameworks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 20:41:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/comparing-declarative-animation-frameworks/</guid><description>A evening of comparing animation in declarative frameworks. A speedrun of the animation system in Jetpack Compose as a comparison agains SwiftUI and Flutter. Hosted by GDG Nuremberg We discovered many similarites, all the systems have some way to control the animation graph, with somewhat confusing differences in naming. A tween in compose is not the same as a tween in Flutter. Flutter Tween is an animationSpec in Compose. Compose tween is a specific kind of Curve in Flutter that does a linear interpolation.</description></item><item><title>Intro to Compose - Live code</title><link>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/intro-to-compose-live-code/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 20:51:01 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/intro-to-compose-live-code/</guid><description>A broad strokes intro to Jetpack Compose followed by a live code demo taster of what it is like to use this framework. The demo ranges from basic use, a bit of Material components and one small animation. Hosted by DevUG. In the second part of the event, Thomas gives us a summary of what&amp;rsquo;s new in Jetpack Compose 1.1
Slides</description></item><item><title>Magic Sprinkles at DevFest UK Ireland</title><link>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/magic-sprinkles-at-devfest-uk-ireland/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 12:53:10 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/magic-sprinkles-at-devfest-uk-ireland/</guid><description>A shorter version of my Magic Sprinkles talk presented at DevFest UK Ireland
Magic Sprinkles: Adding animations to your app with Jetpack Compose
I have some Jetpack Compose UI components in my app and now I want to add animations, where do I start? In this presentation I will look briefly at the Jetpack Compose animation api to get an overview of the animation system. Then I will look at a few quick win simple animations that can add some magic to your app.</description></item><item><title>Confetti Cleanup</title><link>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/confetti-cleanup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 07:37:42 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/confetti-cleanup/</guid><description>In my exploration of animation in Jetpack Compose I built a Confetti modifier that could be applied to any composable. I first showed the modifier in my presentation for Chicago Roboto but since I made it something was bothering me. The way that I can get the state in Compose to register change is by making copies of objects or making new objects. For a modifier that uses particles this can be many objects.</description></item><item><title>Intro to Jetpack Compose</title><link>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/intro-to-jetpack-compose/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 16:36:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/intro-to-jetpack-compose/</guid><description>Introduction to Jetpack Compose technical talk to embeded, mobile and flutter developers. This talk gives an intro to Jetpack Compose and shows how to get started with a simple code lab.</description></item><item><title>Copy Paste Compose</title><link>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/copy-paste-compose/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 16:27:39 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/copy-paste-compose/</guid><description>Devfest 2021 West Sweden lighting talk about Copy Paste Jetpack Compose. CopyPaste is often the first attempt at re-using code, but it has its pitfalls. Some musing on why it seemed easier to copy and paste snippets of code in a Jetpack Compose project. It seems to relate to the composable architecture. Composables can be transplanted easily and modifiers can be grafted from one Composeable to another.
Some pitfalls and things to watch out for and some good places to find code snippets.</description></item><item><title>Two Talks - Magic Sprinkles: adding animations to a Jetpack Compose app</title><link>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/two-talks-magic-sprinkles-adding-animations-to-a-jetpack-compose-app/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 16:10:24 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/two-talks-magic-sprinkles-adding-animations-to-a-jetpack-compose-app/</guid><description>I presented a talk for Chicago Roboto 2021 and for GDG Cape Town titled Magic Sprinkles: Adding animations to and existing app. Below are the videos of both talks and the slides
Chicago Roboto
Slides
Chicago Robot video
GDG Cape Town video</description></item><item><title>Compose meets CameraX</title><link>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/compose-meets-camerax/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 15:57:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/compose-meets-camerax/</guid><description>Co presented a talk with Ishmael about CameraX and integration with Jetpack Compose for GDG Cape Town.</description></item><item><title>Welcome you are visitor number 12345</title><link>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/welcome-you-are-visitor-number-12345/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 21:44:03 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/welcome-you-are-visitor-number-12345/</guid><description>Another step forward in recreating the icon 90s website look is the hit counter, visitor counter or web counter in classic squemorphic odometer style.
hit counters
I was inspired by a recent episode of Code with Italians where they animated a time field. I wanted to change the counter component to animate each number individually to get that odometer look.
Before doing this though there was a question of state.</description></item><item><title>&lt;blink> like it's 1999</title><link>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/blink-like-its-1999/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 17:27:21 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/blink-like-its-1999/</guid><description>Another small experiment to explore Jetpack Compose animations. I came to the conclusion that any value that is passed as a parameter could be animated, including anything in the modifier. So I set out to build a &amp;lt;blink&amp;gt; tag.
My first attempt creates a composable function that takes the modifier, animates it and passes it back to the content lambda. Like this:
@Composable fun BlinkTag( modifier: Modifier = Modifier, durationMillis: Int = 500, content: @Composable (modifier: Modifier) -&amp;gt; Unit ) { val infiniteTransition = rememberInfiniteTransition() val alpha: Float by infiniteTransition.</description></item><item><title>Animating Rainbow Text</title><link>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/animating-rainbow-text/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 00:13:10 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/animating-rainbow-text/</guid><description>Do you remember web pages in the nineties? Everything was pulsing, rotating and animating. I am exploring Jetpack Compose animations and I figured if I can reproduce a 90s web page look, I can do anything. Also June is the month of Rainbows. So to kick off this series I am building animating rainbow text.
First I need a rainbow. It needs to be flexible enough for me to be able to swap in any rainbow.</description></item><item><title>Random Animating Pie Button</title><link>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/random-animating-pie-button/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 21:36:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/random-animating-pie-button/</guid><description>I am exploring animations with small sampler functions using Jetpack Compose. This one is a custom component that draws a little pie chart. It will animate a random pie value on the click of the button.
click and animate
data class PieData( val foreground: Color = Color.White, val strokeWidth: Dp = 4.dp, val percentage: Float ) @Composable fun PieStatus( modifier: Modifier = Modifier, pieData: PieData ) { var animationPlayed by remember { mutableStateOf(false) } val currentPercentage = animateFloatAsState( targetValue = if (animationPlayed) pieData.</description></item><item><title>International Womens Day Codelab - Getting started with Compose</title><link>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/international-womens-day-codelab-getting-started-with-compose/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 15:44:02 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/international-womens-day-codelab-getting-started-with-compose/</guid><description>Getting started with Jetpack compose Codelab and talk for International Women&amp;rsquo;s Day event with Women Techmakers and GDGs in Southern Africa</description></item><item><title>Jetpack Compose - As good as the hype?</title><link>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/jetpack-compose-as-good-as-the-hype/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 15:36:17 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/jetpack-compose-as-good-as-the-hype/</guid><description>Co presented with Charles Okot an first look at Jetpack and how we could use it.</description></item></channel></rss>