<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>animate on maiatoday</title><link>https://maiatoday.github.io/tags/animate/</link><description>Recent content in animate on maiatoday</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 07:37:42 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://maiatoday.github.io/tags/animate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Confetti Cleanup</title><link>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/confetti-cleanup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 07:37:42 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/confetti-cleanup/</guid><description>In my exploration of animation in Jetpack Compose I built a Confetti modifier that could be applied to any composable. I first showed the modifier in my presentation for Chicago Roboto but since I made it something was bothering me. The way that I can get the state in Compose to register change is by making copies of objects or making new objects. For a modifier that uses particles this can be many objects.</description></item><item><title>Welcome you are visitor number 12345</title><link>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/welcome-you-are-visitor-number-12345/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 21:44:03 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/welcome-you-are-visitor-number-12345/</guid><description>Another step forward in recreating the icon 90s website look is the hit counter, visitor counter or web counter in classic squemorphic odometer style.
hit counters
I was inspired by a recent episode of Code with Italians where they animated a time field. I wanted to change the counter component to animate each number individually to get that odometer look.
Before doing this though there was a question of state.</description></item><item><title>&lt;blink> like it's 1999</title><link>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/blink-like-its-1999/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 17:27:21 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/blink-like-its-1999/</guid><description>Another small experiment to explore Jetpack Compose animations. I came to the conclusion that any value that is passed as a parameter could be animated, including anything in the modifier. So I set out to build a &amp;lt;blink&amp;gt; tag.
My first attempt creates a composable function that takes the modifier, animates it and passes it back to the content lambda. Like this:
@Composable fun BlinkTag( modifier: Modifier = Modifier, durationMillis: Int = 500, content: @Composable (modifier: Modifier) -&amp;gt; Unit ) { val infiniteTransition = rememberInfiniteTransition() val alpha: Float by infiniteTransition.</description></item><item><title>Animating Rainbow Text</title><link>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/animating-rainbow-text/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 00:13:10 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/animating-rainbow-text/</guid><description>Do you remember web pages in the nineties? Everything was pulsing, rotating and animating. I am exploring Jetpack Compose animations and I figured if I can reproduce a 90s web page look, I can do anything. Also June is the month of Rainbows. So to kick off this series I am building animating rainbow text.
First I need a rainbow. It needs to be flexible enough for me to be able to swap in any rainbow.</description></item><item><title>Random Animating Pie Button</title><link>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/random-animating-pie-button/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 21:36:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maiatoday.github.io/p/random-animating-pie-button/</guid><description>I am exploring animations with small sampler functions using Jetpack Compose. This one is a custom component that draws a little pie chart. It will animate a random pie value on the click of the button.
click and animate
data class PieData( val foreground: Color = Color.White, val strokeWidth: Dp = 4.dp, val percentage: Float ) @Composable fun PieStatus( modifier: Modifier = Modifier, pieData: PieData ) { var animationPlayed by remember { mutableStateOf(false) } val currentPercentage = animateFloatAsState( targetValue = if (animationPlayed) pieData.</description></item></channel></rss>