<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Knowledge Management Systems Metadata on maiatoday</title><link>https://www.maiatoday.net/tags/knowledge-management-systems-metadata/</link><description>Recent content in Knowledge Management Systems Metadata on maiatoday</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 21:33:17 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.maiatoday.net/tags/knowledge-management-systems-metadata/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>From CLI to CLI - Gemini and Obsidian</title><link>https://www.maiatoday.net/p/from-cli-to-cli-gemini-and-obsidian/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 21:33:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.maiatoday.net/p/from-cli-to-cli-gemini-and-obsidian/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://www.maiatoday.net/p/from-cli-to-cli-gemini-and-obsidian/geminiObsidian.png" alt="Featured image of post From CLI to CLI - Gemini and Obsidian" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s talk about the &amp;ldquo;Obsidian Paralysis.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a while, I’ve been using Obsidian to jot down ideas, plan content, and collect those random snippets from the internet that feel like digital gold. I moved over from Notion a while back. The freedom of simple Markdown managed by Git was liberating. Pure, texty goodness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But—and there&amp;rsquo;s always a &lt;em&gt;but&lt;/em&gt;, isn&amp;rsquo;t there?—one thing always held me back. That nagging little voice: &lt;em&gt;Am I doing it right?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know, I know. The &amp;ldquo;experts&amp;rdquo; say just write the notes and let the system emerge organically. But I was forever second-guessing myself. Is this a &lt;code&gt;status: NotStarted&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;status: not-started&lt;/code&gt;? Is the &lt;code&gt;type&lt;/code&gt; a &amp;ldquo;thought&amp;rdquo; or a &amp;ldquo;note&amp;rdquo;? I was spending more time fiddling with the taxonomy and the metadata &amp;ldquo;meta-system&amp;rdquo; than actually &lt;em&gt;creating content&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But today, everything changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I opened Obsidian and saw the news: &lt;strong&gt;they now have a CLI interface.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💡: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;What if I introduced the &lt;a class="link" href="https://help.obsidian.md/cli" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Obsidian CLI&lt;/a&gt; to an AI Agent CLI?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my experiments, I called in &lt;a class="link" href="https://geminicli.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Gemini CLI&lt;/a&gt;. I basically sat them down in a terminal together, let Gemini CLI figure out what the Obsidian CLI could do, and then—with a spicy mix of &lt;code&gt;grep&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;sed&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;awk&lt;/code&gt;, and the new Obsidian commands, we went to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the &amp;ldquo;Metadata Makeover&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="1-the-status-cleanup"&gt;1. The Status Cleanup
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had Gemini pull every single &lt;code&gt;Status&lt;/code&gt; property from every note in my vault to analyze them for consistency. It detected patterns I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know I had (like all the versions of &lt;code&gt;Idea&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;Ideas&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;Research&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;researching&lt;/code&gt;). We cleaned up the mess, documented the new &amp;ldquo;Golden Rules&amp;rdquo; for statuses, and Gemini wrote a validation script that I can run that will clean things up or highlight inconsistencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="2-the-type-vs-contenttype-tangle"&gt;2. The &amp;ldquo;Type&amp;rdquo; vs. &amp;ldquo;ContentType&amp;rdquo; Tangle
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We did the same for &lt;code&gt;Type&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;ContentType&lt;/code&gt;. It turns out I was using them interchangeably like a chaotic neutral character. Gemini helped me settle on a single source of truth, updated my docs, and tweaked the validation script to keep things tidy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="3-the-tag-jungle"&gt;3. The Tag Jungle
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We looked at everything—frontmatter tags, in-document hashtags, you name it. Gemini analyzed the &amp;ldquo;Tag Jungle&amp;rdquo; and suggested a hierarchy that actually makes sense for how I think. No more &lt;code&gt;tag: gardening&lt;/code&gt; vs &lt;code&gt;#plants&lt;/code&gt; confusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="4-let-the-scripts-do-the-walking"&gt;4. Let the Scripts Do the Walking
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The output wasn&amp;rsquo;t the cleanup but a way to spot patterns, check and cleanup in future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main takeaway? Since this Obsidian CLI release, I can finally stop worrying about whether my metadata is &amp;ldquo;right.&amp;rdquo; I have a system that checks itself, so I can get back to the fun part: just writing. If the system evolves in future which it inevetably will, I can just re-analyse everything, detect the patternsm update the docs and the script and clean everything up again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it is this easy to figure out the real system and fix everything then it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if I am inconsistent for a bit.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>